Edward Anderson

edward@nilbus.com · https://nilbus.com

EDUCATION

GEORGIA TECH

MASTERS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE 2014 - 2017, 3.50 GPA

Coursework

Software Engineering Information Security Machine Learning Artificial Intelligence

CAPSTONE PROJECT

Collaborated with Katrina Owen (GitHub issue) to study gamification's effect on intrinsic motivation in code reviewers on exercism.io.

NC STATE UNIVERSITY **BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

3.57 GPA

President of NCSU Linux Users Group,

College of Engineering Outstanding Senior Award for Leadership Marshal for Computer Science Graduation Ceremony, 3 semesters Chinese Language Department's Outstanding Achievement Award

SKILLS

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

8 years, 25+ apps, 100k+ lines Ruby and Rails JavaScript / CoffeeScript Deployment Automation

DEVOPS INFRASTRUCTURE

1.5 years hands-on

Docker for Devs • Application Metrics Continuous Delivery • On-Call Alerting Continuous Integration • Dev Tooling AWS • Google Cloud Platform Feature Flag Release

6 months research & planning Kubernetes • PCI Security Compliance Docker Swarm • Distributed Storage

LINKS

GitHub:// nilbus LinkedIn:// nilbus Twitter:// @nilbus portfolio:// nilbus.com blog://blog.nilbus.com

SUMMARY

Senior/Lead Software Engineer w/ 8 years developing Ruby on Rails web applications. Recent Georgia Tech Computer Science Masters grad w/ Machine Learning & Al focus. Excels at shipping software efficiently and improving user & developer experience.

EXPERIENCE

ON-SITE remote, from Holly Springs, NC **DEVOPS LEAD**

Apr - Sept 2017

Promoted to focus exclusively on improving our **engineering efficiency** because of my effectiveness in this area, both as a manager and as a software engineer.

- Identified our deployment process as the #1 bottleneck in our value stream
- Planned a migration from on-prem VMs to cloud-based **Docker** & **Kubernetes**
- Addressed security goals and EI3PA (PCI) compliance for containers
- Inspired team & individual change toward **backward-compatible migrations**. 12-Factor App, ChatOps, Infrastructure as Code, Continuous Delivery
- Completed planning for a move to RealPage infrastructure after our acquisition

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER

Jan 2016 - Apr 2017

- Managed and mentored 3 teams: 10 development and operations engineers
- Hired 6 excellent engineers after implementing a consistent and useful **interview process**; screened all candidates and extended offers to our best
- Directed the addition of monitoring, metric instrumentation, centralized logging, and an on-call rotation, decreasing Mean Time To Recover
- Coordinated activity surrounding outages, providing leadership during events
- Worked constantly to **remove pain points** and **improve developer experience**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Apr 2013 - Jan 2016

- Extended and maintained a 17-year-old hybrid **JRuby/Java/Rails** application
- Implemented **RESTful APIs** for **SOA** cross-service communication
- Adhered to **TDD/BDD** testing philosophy with all new features
- Transitioned our team to an improved branching strategy and **Jenkins CI**
- Instituted a weekly Lunch & Learn training; taught advanced Git conflict resolution, OO design, navigating Git blame, reversible deployments, and more
- Saved thousands annually by automating renter screening dispute filing
- Automated QA setup & production deploy: cut turnaround from 4 days to 1 hr

SCIMED SOLUTIONS Durham, NC

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2010 - Mar 2013

- Crafted custom **Ruby on Rails** applications for consulting clients
- Maintained Rails **API back-end** for mobile applications
- Built highly usable interfaces using **Backbone.js** and **jQuery**
- Interfaced directly with clients as a project manager and client liaison
- Open-sourced capistrano-windows-server gem for Windows deployments
- Taught conventions, refactoring, and tools at 20+ training meetings

THE NINTH CUT remote, from Raleigh, NC

TECHNICAL CO-FOUNDER

Jan 2008 - Apr 2010

Launched entertainment database site built on Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and AWS